#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/hinh-nguyen (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

**VMware** 

Virtualization

Windows System Administration

## Languages

English (Full Professional)
Vietnamese (Native or Bilingual)

## Certifications

VCP 5 MCSA 2003

MCSE 2008

# Hinh Nguyen

DevOps Engineer at Fossil Group, Inc.

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

## Summary

08+ years of experience as a DevOps Engineer/System Engineer in multiple working style: startup/enterprise/outsource with many cultures: Vietnam, Singapore, US and Canada.

- Skilled in AWS, GCP, Terraform, CI/CD, K8S, Helm/Flux, VMware, Linux and Windows.
- "Keep Calm and Automate All The Things"

# Experience

Fossil Group, Inc.
DevOps Engineer
October 2018 - Present (6 years 6 months)
HCMC, Viet Nam

Infrastructure as Code as much as possible:

- Provide and manage AWS/GCP resources by Terraform: 08+ separate AWS-Global and AWS-China accounts for production, staging, development and POC environments with cloud services EC2, S3, Route53, RDS, DocDB, MSK, etc. Total monthly bill ~\$80k USD.
- Operate in-house K8S clusters by Kops, Kubectl and Fluxcd: a medium-size, scalable K8S cluster with HA control-plan and 100+ worker nodes.
- Automatically deploy microservices on K8S with CI/CD tools: Bitbucket Pipeline, Docker repository, Helm Chart, Fluxcd, ChartMuseum. Average 20-50 releases/deployments per day.

Auvenir, a Deloitte Venture DevOps Engineer October 2017 - September 2018 (1 year) Toronto, Canada

- Design, implement, manage AWS resources by Terraform, Bash scripts and Ansible: 100+ EC2 instances in 20+ environments (05 projects x 3-5 environments: LB, Web, App, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, RabbitMQ, etc).
- Design and implement CI/CD flow with GitHub, Jenkins, S3 and Ansible: 100+ Jenkins jobs.
- Manage AWS account: IAM permission, network, VPC peering by Terraform.

Page 1 of 4

Mediastep Software Inc.

DevOps Engineer

October 2017 - September 2018 (1 year)

HCMC, Vietnam

Provide DevOps as a services for Auvenir - a finance company at Toronto, Canada

#### Sentifi

DevOps Engineer

September 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 1 month)

HCMC, Vietnam

Start the DevOps role:

- Operate Data Streaming System of Big Data with 5+ data flows and 20+ million messages per day.
- Manage AWS/GCP with 200+ compute instances.
- Migrate cloud infrastructure from AWS to GCP.

#### IBM

VMware System Engineer (contractor - remote working) August 2015 - August 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Vietnam and multiple timezones

Work with IBM as a partner contractor, project CMS (Cloud Managed Services), BHT-SystemX-VMware team:

- Implement and operate VMware infrastructure for 15+ Datacenters on global scale, 300+ servers and devices each Datacenter, high availability up to 99.999%
- Participate in 24/7 on-call rotation. SLA response time is 2 hours.
- Troubleshoot problems, resolve issues and root cause analysis for VMware infrastructure, IBM SystemX server, SAN, network, etc.

## **Optimum Solutions**

3 years

Senior System Engineer & VMware Solution Consultant November 2013 - October 2015 (2 years)

Vietnam and Singapore

On-site projects with Singapore clients:

- Virtualization Infrastructure Migration: Migrate end-of-life system to new high-availability infrastructure in Main site and Backup site (02 sites with physical servers, networks, SAN system, VMware vSphere suite, Veeam, Microsoft Windows, IIS, MS SQL).

- Infrastructure Upgrade and Optimization: resources upgrade and optimization for high-load business operations (Servers, networks, Dell SAN, VMware products).
- Disaster Recovery exercise: training and exercise for customer's employees.

## System Engineer

November 2012 - October 2013 (1 year)

Vietnam

Learn and experience many roles and many failures in the start-up environment:

- Implement and operate Public Cloud Services with VMware vSphere suite, vCloud suite and NSX.
- Research and release high-performance storage with ZFS, FreeNAS and VMware vSAN.

## **VNG** Corporation

Associate System Engineer

March 2012 - October 2012 (8 months)

HCMC, Vietnam

VNG Fresher Program and work in Infrastructure Platform department:

- Datacenter level 2 support for NOC team with 2000+ physical servers and devices: direct (on-site) and remote (server console) support.
- Operate 10+ VMware vCenter clusters, 200+ ESXi hosts and ~10TB Data Storage.
- Provisioning ~300 physical servers and virtual machines monthly. Physical server migration to VM.

## **FPT Information System**

Junior System Engineer (Internship & Part-time)

June 2011 - February 2012 (9 months)

HCMC, Vietnam

\$ bash ./hello\_world.sh:

- Implement Conference Room with 50+ users for Australia partner.
- Run ~1TB data backup weekly for Banking partner.
- Computers/servers/networks incident support for 150+ users in 3-5 partner locations.

# Education

University of Information Technology

Network / System Engineer, Computer Systems Networking and Telecommunications · (2008 - 2012)